早安
Good morning!
寿星驾到
There's the birthday boy!
蛋糕上插满了65根蜡烛
65 candles on one cake.
今天可是你的大日子
This is a big day for you...
以及那些从太空都能看到蜡烛的宇航员们
and for the astronauts who can see it from space.
生日快乐
Happy birthday to you.
谢了  你们知道  我就想安静地过一天
Thank you. And just so everyone knows, I want a quiet day.
别给我惊喜
No surprises.
不要惊喜
昨晚  我发现我怀孕了
Last night, I found out that I am pregnant,
所以有个大惊喜正等着杰呢
so Jay's gonna get one big surprise.
好吧   两个惊喜
Okay, two
如果印着比基尼的烧烤围裙也算上的话
if you count the barbecue apron with the bikini body on it.
也不能怪你  杰
I don't blame you, Jay.
你这辈子体验过够多的惊喜了
You'd had enough excitement in one lifetime--
飞机的诞生  印刷术的发明  农业的出现
The dawn of flight, printed books, agriculture.
这些玩笑是什么意思
All right, what's with all the jokes?
这叫做吐槽
It's insult comedy.
我上网看了迪安·马丁吐槽大会
I've been watching old Dean Martin roasts online.
忘了这老兄不懂什么是网
Like this guy knows from the internet.
有天早上
The other morning,
我看到他在找汽车的手摇启动把呢
I saw him looking for the crank on the front of his car.
[早期汽车需以人力带动发动机]
-够了  别说了  -我只想逗大家一乐而已
- Okay, you're done. - I make fun, and we laugh.
不过说真的
But in all seriousness,
要是你今天见到一道亮光  千万别走过去
if you see a light today, don't walk towards it.
[传说人死后会见到光  重新进入轮回]
抱歉  昨晚你回家时我已经睡着了
I'm sorry I was asleep when you got home.
小卡和米奇一定很失望
Cam and Mitch must be disappointed.
他们为了领养那孩子  下了不少工夫
They were really geared up to get that kid.
但凡事也都有积极的一面嘛
But there's a silver lining.
你说得对  养婴儿麻烦可多了
You might be right. Babies are a lot of work.
不  我不是那个意思
No, that's not what I mean.
-我是  -再说他们也不年轻了
- I'm-- - Ah, you know, and these two aren't getting any younger.
那种年纪可不要再重新开始
The last thing they need is to start over.
真有那么糟糕吗
Would that be so bad?
你好啊  杰
Hey, Jay.
你们来干嘛
What are you doing?
-那是什么玩意  -什么
- What the heck is that? - What?
上
Get him!
关于他的65岁寿辰
Jay has been very explicit
杰清楚明白地表达过他的愿望
about what he wants to do for his 65th birthday,
但菲尔·邓菲善于读懂他暗含的意思
but Phil Dunphy reads between the lines.
你们干什么  搞什么飞机
What the hell is going on?! What are you doing?!
你的生日愿望就要成真了
Making your birthday dreams comes true.
今天是你的好日子哦  老弟
It's your special day, buddy.
该把他关在后备箱里吗
Should we put him in the trunk？
把他关在后备箱干什么
Why would we put him in the trunk?
你不是说怎么玩都不为过吗
You said there were no bad ideas.
把这蠢玩意取下来
Get this stupid thing off me!
你说头套能让他平静下来的
I thought you said the hood would calm him down.
这招对我的猎鹰就管用
It works with my falcon.
别担心  歌洛莉亚  晚餐时间就送他回来
Don't worry, Gloria. We'll have him back in time for dinner.
对他来说  那就是下午4点了
Which for him is at 4:00 in the afternoon.
因为他是老人家  真好笑
'Cause he's old! I love it!
这咖啡真不错
This is really good coffee.
的确如此
It really is.
这是中度烘焙还是
Ahh. Is it a medium roast or...
深度烘培
Uh, dark.
我想说深度  话到嘴边怎么成了中度
Oh. I was gonna say dark. I don't know why I said medium.
你本来肯定可以说对的
Well, you would've been right.
加的是全脂牛奶还是
Is it whole milk or...
-含脂2%  -含脂2%
- 2%. - 2%.
够了  这太荒唐了
Okay. This is ridiculous.
[比喻明显存在的  但大家都刻意忽视的问题]
我们得谈谈客厅里的那只大象了
We need to talk about the elephant in the room.
这只巨型填充大象
The giant stuffed elephant
是我们的好基友胡娇送的礼物
was a gift from our good friend Pepper.
同志家庭养小孩算是新鲜事
Gay guys having kids is-- it's relatively new,
所以基友们不太懂得
so our community has not yet learned
该送婴儿什么礼物
how to modulate baby gifts.
当斯蒂芬和斯特凡的罗可出生时
When Steven and Stefan had little Rocco,
基友朗吉娜请来了
our friend Longinus sent over
嘎巴宝宝节目的全体演员
the whole cast of "Yo gabba gabba".
如今罗可一见鲜亮的颜色就哭
Now Rocco cries whenever he sees bright colors.
我都不能去他家了
I'm not allowed over there.
我看我们还是把它捐给谁吧
I guess we should donate it somewhere,
顺便把那千斤重的大猩猩也捐了
along with the 800-pound gorilla.
既然我们不准备领养宝宝了
I mean, you know, now that we're not getting a baby.
顺便一提  这个决定
A decision, by the way,
天亮以后更显得无比英明
which seems even better in the light of day.
我也这么觉得
Mm. No, I totally agree.
-我们没事了  -根本是好极了
- So we're good? - No, we're great.
-这事解决得太完美了  -没错
- We couldn't have handled this any better. - No.
我的新弟弟呢
Where's my new baby brother?
好吧  还忘了这个小家伙
Okay. Uh, slight oversight.
我想看看他  能给他取名拉里吗
Can I see him? Can we name him Larry?
宝贝  过来坐在爸爸们中间
Okay, sweetie. Here, have a seat with us.
听我说
Um, listen.
有件事我们必须告诉你
There's something we need to tell you.
是关于拉里的吗
Is it about Larry?
那个  算是吧
Well, uh, yes. Uh, sort of.
事实上  我们无法领养一个新宝宝
Um, it--it turns out that... We're not getting a baby.
我知道你因此而难过
Yeah, and I know this-- this makes you very sad,
但我保证我们家还是
but I promise you we're still a family--
我能养只猫吗
Can I have a kitten?
猫
A kitten?
如果没有新弟弟
If I can't have a brother,
那我就要养只叫拉里的猫
then I want a kitten named Larry.
怎么回事  拉里是哪个动画片中的人物吗
Okay, w-what's this about? Is Larry on a show?
没有  所以才特别诡异
He's not, which is what's weird.
-舞会玩得开心吗  -特别开心
- Ooh! How was prom? - So fun.
迈克和我跳了一整晚
Michael and I danced all night...
然后我们留下帮忙打扫会场
And then we stayed after and helped clean up,
那也是件大好事
which was awesome
因为我见到了下学期教三角学的老师
because I got to meet next year's trig teacher.
我记忆中的舞会可不是这样的
That is not the prom I remember.
我头痛死了
I have such a bad headache!
这才是我记忆中的舞会
That's the prom I remember.
你喝酒了吗
Were you drinking?
妈  你非得又跟我来这一套吗
Mom, do we really have to do this?
你问我喝酒了吗  我坚决否认
You ask if I was drinking, I say "No,"
可你我都知道那不是真的
and we both know that that's not true.
我们不是早就玩腻这一套了吗
I mean, aren't we past this point in our relationship?
才怪  小姑娘  我们才没有
No, young lady, we are not.
那我就没喝酒
Then I wasn't drinking.
我也没喝  邓夫人
Me neither, mrs. D.
我的天  别告诉我他在家里过夜了
Dear God. Tell me he did not spend the night here.
妈  你非要又跟我来这一套吗
Mom, do we really have to do this?
妈  我需要做出一个重大决定
Mom, I have a big decision to make
是关于今年的诗歌夏令营的
about poetry camp this summer.
又是关于要带哪根手杖吗
Is this about the walking sticks again?
全带上  等你到了那儿再决定用哪根吧
Pack them all and decide when you're there.
我可以主攻十四行诗和自由诗体
I can either focus on sonnets or free verse.
我一直自诩为十四行诗大师
I've always fancied myself a sonneteer,
但我在想  那些推崇自由诗体的女孩
But I'm thinking the free verse girls
在那方面应该也很"自由"
will be freer with everything,
你懂我的意思吧
If you catch my meaning.
对不起  曼尼
Hmm? Ay. I'm sorry, Manny.
我相信你一定能做出正确的决定
I'm sure you will make the right decision.
你没事吧  你似乎心不在焉的
Are you okay? You seem distracted.
曼尼  快坐下  我得告诉你一些事
Manny, sit down. I have to tell you something.
什么
What?
我怀孕了
I am pregnant.
你什么
You're what?
我又要当妈了
I'm going to have a baby.
哇
Wow.
怎么
What?
你不开心吗
You're not happy?
开心  当然开心
Yeah. Sure.
只是消息太猛  一时难以接受
It's just a lot to take in.
老实说  新生命来的真不是好时候
And I'll be honest, this isn't coming at a great time for me,
我现在有一大堆事要忙
With everything I've got going on.
照顾孩子又不是你的责任
This is not your responsibility.
家里的木制沙拉碗也不是我的责任啊
Neither is our wooden salad bowl,
但只有我给它涂油
But I'm the only one who oils it.
没有我  那木碗会像海绵一样吸光沙拉料
Without me, that thing would soak up dressing like a sponge.
曼尼  我可以照顾好宝宝的
Manny, I can take care of a baby.
我成功地把你照顾长大
I took care of you.
拜托  我是个奇才  我自学的怎么用便壶
Please. I was an anomaly. I self-potty trained.
当年幼小的我就是不明白
I just did not get the appeal
为什么要故意把屎尿拉在裤子上呢
of intentionally soiling one's pants.
然而鉴于此
That said,
我也承认很怀念妈妈在我小肚子上的亲亲
I will admit to missing the kisses on my tummy.
杰是什么反应
How did Jay take it?
我还没有告诉他
I haven't been able to tell him yet.
他可能不会太欣喜
He might not be too thrilled.
你这么想吗  我也开始这么想了
Do you think? I was starting to wonder the same thing.
他不喜欢接受改变
He doesn't deal well with change.
我知道
I know.
他现在还每天都在前门查看晚报到了没有
He still checks the front step for the evening paper.
别担心  妈  我相信他会适应的
Don't worry, mom. I'm sure he'll adapt.
尽管  他现在还把遥控器叫做"敲控器"
Although, he still does call the remote the "Clicker."
是啊
Ay, yeah.
我好无聊  爹地  让汽车跳舞吧
I'm bored, daddy. Make the car dance.
好吧  但只能跳一会儿  好吗
All right. But just for a second, all right?
再来一次
Do it again.
不  一次就够了
No. Once was enough.
如果我不能有个弟弟  那我就要汽车跳舞
If I can't have a brother, then I want the car to dance.
你还真会一次又一次地用这招啊
Wow, you are really comfortable playing that card.
他们不收
They wouldn't take 'em.
他们害怕这些东西身上有臭虫
They were afraid they might have bedbugs.
开什么玩笑  他们拒绝了我们的捐赠吗
Are you serious? They rejected our donation?
我深感被冒犯
I was so offended,
差点没买这个小奶油壶
I almost didn't buy this fiestaware creamer.
只要2块哦
2 bucks.
之前还不知道他们有这好东西呢
Didn't know what they had.
哈  扳回一分
Ah! Score.
我们接下来要干什么
So what are we gonna do now?
弄只猫  然后给它取名拉里
Get a kitten and then name it Larry.
莉莉  亲爱的  现在养猫不合适
Lily, honey, this is hardly the day to get a kitten, okay?
你能跟她说说吗
Would you just tell her?
我不知道
I don't know.
我现在也想弄一只
I kinda want one now.
我们经历了太多的不愉快
You know, we have been through a lot,
或许领回家一只有爱的小宠物
And maybe the presence of a cuddly little friend
能帮助我们愈合心中的伤口
will help us ease the pain.
好吧  你的意思是说
Okay, so what you're saying is,
你心中有个婴儿形状的伤口
You have a child-shaped hole in your heart,
你打算用一只猫去堵住那伤口吗
And your plan is to cram a cat into there?
他是有名字的
He has a name.
我等不及看到你的眼睛重见光明时
I can't wait till your eyes adjust to the light,
你脸上那惊喜的表情
and we see the look on your face.
我恨你们
I hate you guys.
嘿  菲尔  你想过要留胡子吗
Hey, Phil, you ever think about growing a beard?
我是说  你的脸型很适合的
I mean, you got the face for it.
-你那样觉得吗  -是啊
- You think? - Yeah.
有意思  我也一直想留  但我老婆不喜欢
That's funny. I always thought so, but my wife doesn't.
她知道个什么啊
Oh, what does she know?
瞧瞧  你鼻子那么有型  眼睛又那么深邃
Come on, you got a great nose, those deep-set eyes.
我是说  你留胡子一定超帅的
I mean, you would look good.
谢谢你  小短
Thanks, Shorty.
[乔·哈姆为名剧《广告狂人》主演
在戏外经常以大胡子形象示人]
有点像乔·哈姆在戏外的造型
It's, uh, sort of a Jon Hamm in between projects.
好了  把我放回车厢里吧
Okay, put me back in the trunk.
放松  你就快到了
Relax, you're almost there.
不  我不干了
Nope, I'm done now!
-嘿  杰  -不  不  不
- Hey, jay, no! - No! No! No! Hey!
杰  杰
Jay! Jay!
-杰  -狗娘养的
- Jay! - Son of a bitch!
快来个人救我
Somebody help me!
我也想啊  但我的裤子是山羊绒的
I would, but--but these pants are cashmere!
我来救你  杰
I got you, Jay!
你得让他冷静下来
You gotta calm him down!
-打他的头  -别打他的头
- Punch him in the head! - Don't punch him in the head!
别逼我打晕你  我会为了救你打晕你的
Don't make me punch you! I will punch you to save you!
我觉得我像是在被施水刑一样
I think I'm being waterboarded.
是你逼我的
You're making me do this!
把这玩意儿拿下来
Get this thing off me!
生日快乐
Happy birthday.
我们是打算带你钓鱼的
We're taking you fishing.
不管怎么说
For whatever it's worth,
迪兰昨晚非常表现得极具责任感
Dylan was very responsible last night.
家里能有他真好
He's a good guy to have around the house.
你到底想说什么
Mm. Where we going with this?
既然我不能搬去和他一起住
Well, since I can't move in with him anymore,
他负担不起他的房租钱
He can't afford his apartment.
所以我在想能不能
So I was wondering if it would be okay
让他和我们一起住几个星期
if he could stay with us for a couple weeks?
当然可以  不如
Sure. Oh, you know what?
把我们的大房间让给你们吧
Why don't you guys take our room?
她那是戏谑的说法
She's being facetious.
就是讽刺
Sarcastic.
迪兰不能搬进来
Dylan no stay.
什么
what?!
拜托  他能帮许多忙
Oh, come on! He helps out a lot.
他手可巧了
He is very handy.
是吗  他不是曾把自己反锁在车里吗
Really? The guy who locked himself in his car?
你没资格开口向我求情  小姐
You are in no position to be asking for favors, young lady.
来  把这个喝了  解酒的
Here. Drink this. It's for your hangover.
闻着太恶心了
Ugh. It smells gross.
那你就快点儿喝嘛
Well, then you better drink it fast.
恶  我要吐了
Ew! I'm gonna throw up! Ugh! Ugh!
那是解酒的吗
That's a hangover cure?
不是
No.
我这手机应该是短路了
Well, this is probably shot.
我得再跟你说声对不起  不该打你头
Once again, I'd like to apologize for punching you in the head.
可是只有这样才能救你
It really was the only way to save you
你当时双手被绑着  头也被  罩着
since you were bound and... hooded,
我还得再为这个道个歉
which leads me to my second apology.
先生们  得了  就像我叔叔常说的
Gentlemen, come on. As my uncle used to say,
别让一次搞砸了的绑架毁了整个午后时光
let's not let a botched kidnapping ruin our whole afternoon.
他说的对  这件事的重点在于
He's right. The whole point of this
让你和三个最好的朋友享受湖上风光
is for you to enjoy the lake with your three best friends.
斯坦来了吗
Stan coming?
好受伤
Burn!
菲尔以为是在说别人
65岁了哈
So... 65, huh?
你即将迎来人生中最美好的日子
You're heading into the best years of your life.
说的对
That's right.
你兢兢业业工作过  该爬的山也都爬了
You put in the work. You climbed the mountain.
现在是接受奖赏的时刻了
Now it's time to reap the rewards.
我想你是对的
I guess you're right.
我觉得相当美好啊
Sounds pretty good to me.
你知道吗  我越看你
You know, the more I look at you,
就越气愤你咋不留胡子呢
the angrier I get that you don't got a beard.
我留过灵魂补丁款的[下唇留小撮胡子]
I had a soul patch once.
灵魂补丁  那是胡子界的耻辱
A soul patch? That's like a beard's crap.
我上周打了6次高尔夫
I golfed six times last week.
找到了42颗球  创下新纪录了
found 42 balls-- a new record.
我觉得我的猎鹰肯定找不到那么多
I don't think my falcon could have found that many,
不过它能发现600码开外的老鼠
And he can spot a mouse at 600 yards.
这和胡子有一毛钱关系吗
Whats that have to do with beards?
我们不是在探讨杰已经65岁
I thought we were talking about Jay turning 65
而65岁有多棒的话题吗
and how good that's gonna be.
对啊  这岁数好啊  杰
That's right. It's gonna be great, jay.
我跟你说  我开垦了一片菜地
I'm telling ya. I got a vegetable garden.
两年前  那就是我院子里的一个泥坑
Two years ago, it was a patch of dirt in my backyard.
现在我种上了西红柿  五种豆豆
Now I got tomatoes, I got five kinds of beans,
还有南瓜
I got squash.
我只告诉你
And between you and me,
我都开始考虑自己腌制酸黄瓜了
I'm even thinking about pickling my own cucumbers.
为啥这个只对我说
Why would that be between you and me?
因为腌菜数量有限呐
Because there's a finite number of pickles.
别担心  你俩也有份
But don't worry. All you guys are on the list.
我想来祝个词
Well, I'd like to make a toast.
敬杰  虽然你已经没啥潜力了
To Jay, who's not particularly buoyant.
再次地  我对此深表遗憾
And again, I'm very sorry about that.
但他是世上难寻的绝佳岳父
But he's the best father-in-law a guy could ask for.
我们能够认识他  都非常幸运  干杯
All right. And we're--we're all really lucky to know him. Cheers.
-来  来吧  -祝你健康
- Here, here. - Salud.
谢谢伙计们  你们知道吗
Thanks, guys. You know what?
和你们一起出来非常开心
It is kinda nice being out here with all of ya.
我们钓鱼吧
Hey, let's do some fishing.
我感觉好多了  身上总算快干了
I'm starting to feel better now that I'm finally getting dry.
钓鱼吧
Let's do this!
-走吧  -好的
- Let's go! - All right!
当然
Sure.
你知道吗
You know,
我在毕业舞会上喝了一点儿薄荷杜松子酒
I had a little peppermints schnapps at my prom,
但我瞒过了我的父母
but I hid it from my parents
而且在他们起床前  把我男友弄出了门
and I kicked my boyfriend out before they woke up.
那叫做起码的尊重
It's called respect.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
你要变肥了
You're gonna get fat.
你  我是说
You--oh! I mean...
太好了  太好了  你怀孕了
That's great. It's great! You're pregnant!
棒极了  恭喜你
It's great! Congratulations!
其实是个意外之喜
It was a surprise.
可不是嘛  我爸爸怎么说
Yeah, I'll bet. What did my dad say?
我还没有告诉他
I haven't told him yet.
我担心他会觉得这个不是个好消息
I worry that he's going to think it's not such great news.
不会的  别傻了
Ohh, no. Don't be silly.
他会高兴死的
He's gonna be thrilled.
我知道他才不会高兴呢
I knew he wasn't gonna be thrilled.
如果历史可以为鉴
And if history was any indication,
他也不会掩盖自己情绪的
he wasn't gonna be able to hide it.
这是一款法式加拿大美味  叫做布丁
It's a french canadian delicacy called poutine.
看着像是别人吐出来的
Mm. Well, it looks like vomit,
我才不会让那东西"补丁"进我嘴里
So I'm not pou-ting it in my mouth.
我们来了
We're here!
你头发怎么了
What'd you do to your hair?
我想尝试一下新发型
I thought I'd try something different.
干嘛  为了显老吗
What, looking old?
我得赶在老爸
I had to get to dad
对歌洛莉亚说出刻薄话前找到他
Before he said something insensitive to Gloria.
但她肯定会变得很肥的
But she is gonna get really fat, though.
爸  给我回电话
Dad, call me back.
我有很重要的事要告诉你
I have something very important to tell you
那样你回家后就不会说些蠢话
So when you get home you don't say something stupid
就像你以前常干的那样
Like you usually do.
噢  生日快乐
oh, happy birthday.
我不得不说
Yeah. I've gotta say,
你对新宝宝一事的反应  比我想的要淡定的多
You're handling this baby thing better than I would've expected.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
你已经习惯了当家里唯一的孩子
You're used to being the only kid in the house.
马上就会多个新的孩子  杰的亲生孩子
Now there's gonna be a new kid. Jay's kid.
那又如何
So?
以前的曼尼肯定会担心
Well, the old Manny would've been worried
杰会更疼爱新出生的孩子
that Jay would love the new kid more.
我觉得你太低估我的可爱乖巧了
I think you're underestimating how adorable I am.
你说得对  你可比小宝宝萌多了
You're right. You're way cuter than a baby.
我去看看晚饭好了没有
I'm gonna go check on dinner.
有时候我就喜欢扔个炸弹  然后走开
Sometimes I just like to toss a grenade and run away.
来  吸一口气
All right, take a whiff.
确定你喜欢这味道哦
Make sure you like it,
因为以后我们家沙发就会是这味儿了
'cause that's what our couch is gonna smell like.
你好  我们就打算要这只了
Okay, hi. Yes, we're gonna take this one.
你们先别急着要
Oh, I'm gonna need you to slow down a bit.
我们有一些手续要办
There's a process we need to go through
以确定你们是否有资格养猫
to see if you're a suitable cat guardian.
噢是吗  我以为手续就是
Oh, really? Because I thought the process was,
我表示看中了这只
I say, "We'll take this one."
而你感激涕零  因为你们囤猫太多
And then you say, "Thank god because we have too many cats."
不  我们得确保它们都能找到好归宿
No. We need to ensure these cats are going to good homes.
所以你们得先填了这张表
That's why we need you to fill out this form,
然后我们会到你们家实地拜访
And then there'll be a site visit.
是这样  一年来我们饱尝各种辛酸麻烦
Okay, um, we've just been through a very frustrating year
就为了领养个孩子  所以
trying to adopt a baby, so...
希望你能体谅我们实在不愿意
You'll forgive us if we're not really in the mood
为一只猫搞得太折腾
to jump through too many hoops for a cat.
为什么你们没领养成功
Oh. Why wouldn't they give you a baby?
-那问题很复杂  -领养猫也是
- It's complicated. - So are cats.
是吗  那边那只猫一直在舔自己
Are they? 'cause that one over there has been licking
从我们来一直舔到现在
itself ever since we got here.
好吧  我...我弄不下去了
Okay, you know what? I'm--I can't do this.
拉里怎么办
What about Larry?
抱歉  莉莉  今天不行
I'm sorry, Lily. Not today.
米奇尔一走了之  我可不会善罢甘休
Mitchell stormed off, but I couldn't.
我得给她点颜色瞧瞧
I had to give her a piece of my mind.
结果呢
And how'd that go?
我想我可能跑偏了一点点
I may have strayed off topic just a bit.
不可能  大姐
No, sir!
不  在我心中她永远是单纯的诺玛·简[梦露原名]
No, she will always be Norma Jeane Baker to me.
你到底想说什么
What is your point, exactly?
就像离过三次婚的女星
That like the thrice-married starlet,
这只猫被剥夺了享受家庭温暖的权利
This cat is being deprived a stable home.
我很抱歉让你不高兴了
I'm sorry if you're upset.
真正该不高兴的人是你才对吧  女士
You're the one who should be upset, ma'am.
我们可是喜欢动物的爱心人士
we are animals lovers.
那只猫原本可以享"受"最完美的呵护
That cat would've been on the receiving end of affection
24小时不间断
24 hours a day.
满足它的全部需求将成为我们的首要任务
Satisfying its every need would've been our top priority.
好吧  鉴于这样的画面
Okay, in light of that tableau,
我要收回之前说的让那只猫享"受"
I would like to take back the phrase "Receiving end."
老妈  我决定不参加诗歌夏令营了
Mom, I've decided I'm not going to poetry camp.
什么  为什么
What? Why not?
因为等我回来的时候
'cause by the time I come back,
杰会把我的房间变成婴儿房
Jay will have turned my room into a nursery.
不  他不会的
No, he won't.
我不是他亲生的
I'm not his real kid.
我将如狂风中的耳语一般被无视
I'll be as insignificant as a whisper in a windstorm.
瞧你说的  你这么有天赋
Oh, listen to you. You have a gift.
你必须去参加诗歌夏令营
You have to go to the poetry camp.
恐怕我是不会去了
I don't think I can
曼尼拜托  我现在已经够烦心的了
Manny, please. I have too much to worry about right now.
-好吗  -你
-Okay? - You?
我才是自掘坟墓
I dug a pretty big hole for myself
今早说了那么多冒犯他的笑话
with those insult jokes this morning.
为什么我不学学里格斯
Why didn't I learn from Rickles?
得在结束时来点摇摆小舞
You gotta end with some ticker.
算了 我认输
Okay, I give up.
我实在摆不出一个不淫荡的体位
I can't find a position that's not sexual.
-淡定  -我淡定不了
- Just calm down. - I can't calm down.
也许我们没有嘴上说的那么没事
You know, maybe we're not as okay as we keep saying we are.
-我知道  -也许我们该离开一段时间
- I know. - Maybe we should go away.
到一个陌生的地方去疗伤
You know, go someplace to heal.
哪里
Where?
一个拥有华丽剧院的地方
Well, someplace with a vibrant theater scene...
处处是高级餐厅
Top-notch restaurants...
密苏里怀特河畔的风水宝地
The jewel of Missouri's white river.
我们才不要去布兰森
We're not going to Branson.
好吧  你想去哪里
Okay, fine. Where would you go?
不知道  欧洲如何
I don't know. Maybe europe?
伦敦
London?
越远越好
Just somewhere far away.
-我好悲伤  小卡  -我也是
-I'm just sad, Cam.  - I am, too.
我把以后早晨怎么度过都打算好了
You know, I had our mornings all planned out.
我抱着宝宝送莉莉去幼儿园
The baby and I would walk Lily to kindergarten
然后穿过公园回家
and then cut back home through the park
停下来喂喂鸭子  虽然公园不让喂
and feed those ducks that you're not supposed to feed
但大家都在喂
but everybody does.
我买了相框放在桌上
I bought a picture frame for my desk,
它一直在那里静静等待
and it's just sitting there,
他的出现
Waiting for his face.
抱抱
Come here.
我感觉好多了
I already feel better.
我也是
Me, too.
瞧瞧拥抱的力量
See what the power of a hug can do?
省了我们长途跋涉的一路颠簸
Just saved us a long plane ride with a toddler.
-也省了搞一只猫回来  -猫还是得有的
- And a cat that we didn't want. - Oh, we're still getting that.
瞧  看上去如何
All right, how does this look?
超级纯情  都没有肢体接触
Perfectly innocent. They're not even touching.
很好  走吧
Great. Okay. Let's go.
好吧
All right.
坐好了  宝贝
You ready, honey?
去吧  去吧
Go. Go.
你好  邓菲太太
Hey, Mrs. Dunphy?
我听说了海莉问你的事  其实我想告诉你
I heard about what Haley asked you, and just so you know,
我不是有意让你为难
I never wanted to put you in that position.
-没关系的  -那就好
- I'll be fine. - That's good to know.
我表哥迪兰说我可以在他家里住
My cousin Dylan said I could stay at his house.
虽然  其实不是真的家里
Well, not really at his house.
准确的说是...车库
More like behind it... In the garage.
不错啊
Okay.
其实  那里没有墙
Well, actually, there are no walls,
所以更准确的说是停车门廊
So it's more of a porte cochere.
挺好嘛
Fancy.
反正  我就在那里睡
Anyway, I'll be sleeping in it.
那里有卫生间的
It's got a bathroom.
准确的说  是半间
More of a half-bath.
是个咖啡罐
It's a coffee can.
总之  我会过得很好
Anyway, I'll be fine
只要能发现一个抵御郊狼袭击的帐篷就行
once I find a nice tent to protect me from the coyotes.
记得把食物挂在高处
Well, be sure to hang your food up high.
我们回来啦
we're back!
寿星驾到
Birthday boy's here!
杰  你浑身都皱皱的
Hey, Jay, you're all wrinkled.
是啊  你想说我人老皮皱
Yeah, yeah, I'm old. I get it.
不  我是指你的衣服
No, I mean your clothes.
像你这么大的时候  我都披兽皮
Yeah, when I was your age, I was wearing animal skins.
哗  你戏谑到我了
Bam! You got me.
我觉得  哗  你戏谑到你自己了
I think, bam! You got yourself.
我只是表示关心而已
I'm just expressing concern.
让我想想  关心我的骨质密度
Let me guess-- about my bone density.
不得不说  你真是个聪明蛋
You know, you're a real smart-ass.
这样下去  我得住地下室了
At this rate, I'll be living in the basement.
真幸运
Lucky.
爸  爸  快点  过来一下
Dad? Dad, okay, quick. Just come here one second.
我有事跟你说
I gotta tell you something.
有人会告诉你一件非常重要的事情
Somebody is about to tell you some very important news.
这辈子第一次
And for the first time in your life,
请你说些好听的话
I need you to react nicely.
-我总是捡好听的说  -从没有过
- I always react nicely. - You never do.
我说的那个人现在非常脆弱无助
And this person in question is very vulnerable right now.
所以求你一定要表现出关爱与支持
So could you please just be loving and supportive?
-生日快乐  老爸  -谢谢
- Happy birthday, dad! - Oh, thank you.
好孩子
That's a boy.
抱歉我们迟到了  但事出有因
Sorry we're late, but it's for a good reason.
我们考虑养只猫
We're thinking about getting a cat.
那  真是太好了
Well, isn't that wonderful?
我为你们感到激动  这是个重大决定
I'm thrilled for you both. This is a heck of a decision.
我完全支持
You have my full support.
好的
Okay.
家里再添位成员真是太好了
I think it'll be a perfect addition to the family.
我知道我自己会爱死那小家伙的
I know I'll love the heck out of the little bugger.
我只希望那边的小家伙不要吃醋
I'm just hoping that little one over there doesn't get jealous.
噢  "这个小家伙"不会有事的
Oh, this little one will be just fine
现在他知道自己在家是个啥地位了
now that he knows where he stands--
活在你新宝贝的阴影下
In the shadow of your new baby!
他说什么呢
What's he talking about?
他说的是我怀孕的事
He's talking about I am pregnant.
-拜托  -怀孕
- Oh, come on! - Pregnant?!
你开玩笑吧
You gotta be kidding me!
恶心  我没想到外公还能做
Oh, gross. I didn't know grandpa could still do it.
别这么无礼  卢克
Don't be disrespectful, Luke.
面对歌洛莉亚  谁都能硬起来
Anyone could do it with Gloria.
如果你习惯了一成不变的生活  不乐意接受
And if you're too set in your old ways to be happy about it,
我可以一个人养大这孩子
I can raise it on my own.
我以前养过  现在也可以做到
I have done it before, and I can do it now!
我和众多久经考验的坚强拉美女性一样
I come from a very long line of strong Latin women
习惯了不见老公的鬼影
whose husbands are nowhere to be found!
-你说完了吗  -是的
- Are you done? - Yes!
-我能发表意见吗  -请说
- Can I say something? - Go on!
这是我这辈子听到的最棒的消息
That's the greatest news I've ever heard.
是吗
It is?
我一整天都在听我的未来依然光明的鬼话
I spent the day hearing what my future had in store for me,
没一句我爱听的
and I didn't like one bit of it.
感觉像我的人生已经到头了
It felt like my life was ending.
现在你告诉我  我能有个全新的开始
And now you're telling me that I get to have a new start...
和我心爱的女人一起
with the woman of my dreams.
我觉得我快哭了
I think I'm gonna cry.
我早哭了
I'm way ahead of you.
你能相信吗
Can you believe this?
就是说啊  人家连猫都不让我们养
I know. They wouldn't even let us get a cat.
真是太好了
It's gonna be great!
我会变成大肥婆
I'm gonna get so fat.
大部分都挺好[除了变胖]
Mostly great.
恶心  他们又来了
Oh, gross. They're at it again.
你不喜欢就别看
If you don't like it, don't look.
她看起来不错啊  是吧
She looks great, doesn't she?
是啊
Yeah.
我一直腹黑地希望她增肥  没想到是增在肚子上
Not really gaining weight the way I would've expected.
我终于明白了为何大家都说孕妇光彩照人
I finally understand why people say pregnant women glow.
菲尔  我怀过三次
Phil, I have had three children.
爸  歌洛莉亚  拆我们的礼物吧
Hey, dad, Gloria, open our present.
希望是高级货
Ooh! I hope it's something fancy.
是给宝宝的  我好喜欢
It's for the baby. I love it!
我们在希思罗机场买的  免税
We got it in a shop at Heathrow, duty free.
[Duty既指税  又指宝宝拉屎拉尿]
很快就不能"免屎"了
Not for long.
是不是好棒的说
Isn't it absolutely brilliant?
我们在伦敦就待了两周
Okay, we were in london two weeks.
别拽口音了  麦当娜
Lose the accent, Madonna.
你的脸上怎么全是抓痕
Why is your face all scratched up?
白痴拉里干的好事
Stupid Larry.
感觉好怪
This feels so weird.
很适合你
It suits you.
别开没营养的玩笑
Don't even joke about it.
够了  他明天就得给我搬
That's it. He is moving out of the house tomorrow.
真的吗
Really?
你的胡子也得刮
Oh, and that beard is going.
好吧  但小短可得伤心死了
Fine, but it's gonna kill shorty.
好了各位  都过来吧
Okay, everybody, let's gather together.
曼尼将为大家读一段
Manny's gonna read us a little something
他在诗歌夏令营中做的诗
that he prepare in his poetry camp.
多谢  妈
Thank you, mom.
谨以此诗献给我即将到来的弟弟或妹妹
This is for my new baby brother or sister.
欢迎你  小家伙
"Welcome, little one.
张开双眼  融入这个家吧
Open your eyes and take your place.
这里是你命中注定的归宿
This is where you're meant to be,
依偎在母亲的胸前
Nestled in the bosom of your mother."
真幸运的宝宝
Lucky baby.
-什么  -爱你  宝贝
- What? - Love you, baby.
这里是你命中注定的归宿
"This is where you're meant to be,
父亲的怀抱
in the arms of your father.
他的漫长人生造就了今日的他
His long, long journey has readied him for this day,
尽管他的皮肤也许松弛了
though his skin may be loose,
他的头发已稀疏
his hair but a wisp,
岁月的沉淀让他的眼神混浊不清
and his eyes milky with age,"
好了  就念到这里吧
All right, we're done here.
得去喝一杯
Get a drink.
别为你赶我走的事心怀愧疚  邓太太
Don't feel bad about making move out, mrs. D.
我知道这一天终会到来
I knew this day would come eventually,
我有心理准备
and I'm totally covered.
太好了  那我们回见了
Great. So we'll see you around.
我有个老朋友那里有地方
I got a place with an old friend of mine.
与其说地方  不如说是储物间
Well, not so much of a place as a storage pod.
与其说是朋友  不如说是浣熊
And not so much of a... friend as a raccoon.
你有室友我很开心
Good to know you'll have company.
我叫它小泡  因为它的嘴里全是泡沫
I call him bubbles because his mouth is all foamy.
迪兰  你的小把戏我早看穿了
Dylan, I'm on to your little game.
我知道你说的全是假的
I know non of this is ture.
你就是想我内疚  然后让你留下来
You just try to guilt me into I letting you stay.
你说的对  对不起
You're right, I'm sorry.
我住车上好了
I'll just live in my car.
我可以借个衣架吗
Think I can borrow a coat hanger
我怕又被关在车里了
in case I get lock in there again.
-老天  -什么事啊
- God. - What's going on?
不行  全刮掉
No, no no. All of it.
你不想在我恢复天使面容前与魔鬼共舞吗
Sure you don't wanna dance with the devil before I get rid of it.
快去
Go.
好吧
Fine.